

1

+49 (0) 162 775 3627



felipetroves@gmail.com



Große Messergasse 6, Passau



felipetroves.github.io



American and Brazilian

HARD SKILLS

- Design
- Adobe Suite
- Story Telling
- Social Media
- Digital Media
- Programming
- Information Technology
- Video & Audio Production

SOFT SKILLS

- Empathy
- Focus
- Ambition
- Creative Thinking
- Collaboration
- Active Listening
- Discipline
- Information Gathering

LANGUAGES

German: Working Proficiency English: Bilingual Proficiency Portuguese: Bilingual Proficiency

FELIPE REIS

Passionate about the creative process and bringing ideas to life through various mediums. Experienced in working with technology through university projects, internships and work opportunities. Team player with strengths such as empathy, idea gathering, focus and inquisitiveness.

EDUCATION

O APPRENTICE FOR APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT

msg systems | Passau, BY (DE)

October 2022 - present

- Digitization of forms
- Using the Groovy language to customize and troubleshoot processes
- Learning the basics of the IT profession

ACADEMIC GERMAN YEAR

University of Passau | Passau, BY (DE)

October 2021 - July 2022

Achievement: C1 German as Foreign Language Certificate

B.A. IN NEW MEDIA

Purchase College | Purchase, NY (USA)

September 2016 - May 2019

Achievement: Dean's List, Magna Cum Laude (GPA: 3.8)

Relevant Courses:

- Introduction to Media Studies
- Programming for Visual Artists
- Introduction to the Web
- New Directions in Virtual Sapce
- Drawing, Moving, and Seeing with Code

A.A.S. IN PERFORMING ARTS

Westchester Community College | Valhalla, NY (USA)

September 2013 - May 2016

Achievement: President's List (GPA: 3.8)

Relevant Courses:

- Digital Illustration
- Graphic Design
- College Algebra: Functions & Models
- Development of Mathematical Thoughts

INTERESTS

- Traveling
- Hiking
- Art Making
- Making Music
- Game Development/Design
- Web Development/Design

REFERENCES

Martin Köppen

• martin.koeppen@msg.group

Craig Vogel

• craigvogel@gmail.com Mike

Moskowitz

• mfmosk@gmail.com

Justin Britton

• justin.britton@ef.com

Kate Moodie

• kate@katemoodie.com

Rob Diaz

• robd@madsciencenyc.com

CERTIFICATES

German as a Foreign Language

• University of Passau (2022)

120-Hour TEFL

• Foundation TEFL (2020)

Affin Mar

Passau, 15.04.2024

WORK EXPERIENCE

ENGLISH AS A FOREIGN LANGUAGE TEACHER

EF Education First | Tarrytown, NY (USA)

July 2021 - September 2021

English teacher for foreign students (level: A2, B1)

STEM INSTRUCTOR

Computer Adventures | Yonkers, NY (USA)

August 2019 - May 2021

- Technology lessons for children with a focus on concept formation, creativity and problem solving
- Introduction to programming, robotics and stopmotion animation

VIDEO EDITOR

Mood of Living | New York, NY (USA)

November 2020 - May 2021

Development of strategies to increase online reach for digital magazine by creating and editing engaging videos for social media (remote)

VIDEO EDITOR

Barn Burner Music | Irvington, NY (USA)

August 2019 - August 2020

Shooting and editing of promotional videos for local musicians (freelance work in partnership)

PROJECTS

"HUMAN ERA"

Purchase College | Purchase, NY (USA)

September 2018 - May 2019

Bachelor Thesis

- Research and virtual interactive art
- Made with Unity 3D
- Presented as a new media art installation at Purchase College, New York